Guide to the Elliot W. Eisner Papers SC0878
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Papers, Accesion ARCH-2007-245
  - Audiovisual material
    - Junius Eddy, "Bridging the Gap between the Arts and Education,", 5/12/75; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Al Hurwitz, "School Art: the Search for the Avant-Garde,", 5/5/75; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - "Learning Your ABC's" Dobbs/Alexander/Nash, 5/21/75; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - John Levick (?) "Teacher-Child Interaction in the Arts", 2/16/1976; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Jerome Hausman, "Elitism in Art and Egalitarianism in the Community – What's an Art Educator to Do?" 5/19/75, 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Dr. Edmund Feldman, University of Georgia, "Art, Education and the Consumption of Images,", 1975 Apr 14; 1 audiotape(s) (reel-to-reel) (Box 9)
    - Robin Alexander, tape #2, 1 video reel(s) (1 inch) (Box 9)
- Additional Papers, Accesion ARCH-2008-014
  - Abstract: Beliefs and Teaching Practices (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Art Education, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art Education Belief Index, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Beliefs and Teaching Practices of Art Teachers, 1960-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Beliefs and Teaching Practices of Art Teachers Budget, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Beliefs and Teaching Practices of Art Teachers Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Requests for Eisner Art Attitude Inventory and Art Information Inventory Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Curriculum Theory and Curriculum Change Autumn, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Curriculum Theory, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Curriculum Theory, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Curriculum Theory, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Curriculum Development in Art Education (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Foundations of Aesthetic Education, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Kettering Project Key (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Kettering Project 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Kettering Project 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Kettering Project 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Kettering Project 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Kettering Project 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Kettering Project 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Overviews of the Field of Education (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Prospective Art Teachers' Beliefs Manuscript (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Public Lecture Series (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Speeches: Chicago 1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Speeches: Arizona 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Speeches: Stull Act 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Speeches: Birmingham, England (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Speeches: San Diego 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Speeches: New Orleans 1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Doctoral Study in the Field of Art Education (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Eisner Art Attitude Inventory Correspondence 1965, 1966, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Eisner Art Attitude Inventory Correspondence 1968, 1969, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Eisner Art Attitude Inventory Correspondence 1971, 1972, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - INSEA World Congress 1975-1986 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - INSEA World Congress 1977, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Teaching Art to the Young, November 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Kettering Project Correspondence 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Articles: Is the Artist in the School Program Effective? (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Articles: Can Art be Taught? (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Articles: Emerging Models for Educational Evaluation, August 1972 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Articles: Is a New Era in the Humanities Possible? April 1969 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Articles: Evaluation and Research of Curriculum Materials 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Articles: Artistic Learning in American Schools 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Articles: Educational Objectives – Help or Hindrance 1966 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Articles: Examining Some Myths in Art Education (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Articles: Curriculum Development in Stanford's Kettering Project (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Articles: Curriculum Development – Sources for a Foundation for the field of Curriculum (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Requests Eisner Art Attitude Inventory (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Career Education Project 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Career Education Project Correspondence 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Career Education Project Budget (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Career Education Project Expenses 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Papers 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Papers 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Vita (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Articles 1957-1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Papers 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Papers 1971-1974 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Papers 1974-1976 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Papers 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Summer School Program 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Literature (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - INSEA correspondence, Chalmers, Graeme, 1987-90 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - INSEA correspondence, Chavanne, Marie-Francoise, 1987-90 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - INSEA correspondence, Grauer, Kit, 1987-90 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - INSEA correspondence, Kantner, Larry, 1987-90 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - INSEA correspondence, Steers, John, 1987-90 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - INSEA correspondence, Wojnar, Irena, 1987-90 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - ED 213 (Foundations of Aesthetic Education) 1972-78 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - ED 219 (Artistic Development of the Child) 1973-78 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - ED 261A, 261B (Curriculum and Instruction in Art) 1973-75 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - ED 340 (Curriculum Theory and Curriculum Change) 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - ED 340 (Curriculum Theory and Curriculum Change) 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - ED 340 (Curriculum Theory and Curriculum Change) 1972-74 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - ED 342A (Curriculum Construction) 1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - ED 348X (Educational Connoisseurship and Criticism) 1976 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ED 361A [memo that Eisner is not teaching it Summer 1973] (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - ED 380 (Curriculum Development in the Visual Arts) 1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - ED 440 (Seminar in the School Curriculum) 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - ED 441A & B (doctoral seminar) 1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - ED 461A (doctoral seminar) 1975 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - ED 463 (doctoral seminar) 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Curriculum Development in the Visual Arts, 1976-77 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Stanford in Germany, Winter 1974 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - STEP Art Bibliography (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Getty Museum Education Study (1 of 2) 1984 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Getty Museum Education Study (2 of 2) 1984 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Museum education – assorted papers (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - "The Territory of Art," Museum of Contemporary Art, LA (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2018-053
  - Chronological Files
    - 1972-1974 (Box 1)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - 1992-1995 (Box 3)
    - 1995-1996 (Box 4)
  - Subject Files
    - A-Bo, circa 1990s (Box 5-6)
    - B-G, circa 1990s (Box 7)
    - Bo-Da, circa 1990s (Box 8)
    - De-Du, circa 1990s (Box 9)
    - Du-Ei, circa 1990s (Box 10)
    - Ei - F, circa 1990s (Box 11)
    - Ga-Ge, circa 1990s (Box 12)
    - Ge, circa 1990s (Box 13)
    - Hu-Ke, circa 1990s (Box 14)
    - I-K, circa 1990s (Box 15)
    - Ke -, circa 1990s (Box 16)
    - M-N, circa 1990s (Box 17)
    - N-P, circa 1990s (Box 18)
    - P-Si, circa 1990s (Box 19)
    - Si-St, circa 1990s (Box 20)
    - Su-W, circa 1990s (Box 21)
    - W-Z, circa 1990s (Box 22)
  - Courses
    - circa 1970s-1990s (Box 23-25)
  - Professional
    - INSEA (Box 26-27)
    - AERA (Box 28)
    - NAEA, 1970s-1980s (Box 29, Box 31)
    - Miscellaneous Professional Files (Box 30, Box 32, Box 33)
  - Publications
    - Miscellaneous Publications (Box 34)